<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Physics | Daily (?) Complaints (?)]]></title>
  <link href="http://zmwangx.github.io/blog/categories/physics/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://zmwangx.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-11-20T10:41:00-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://zmwangx.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Zhiming Wang]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Interstellar]]></title>
    <link href="http://zmwangx.github.io/blog/2014/11/07/interstellar/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-07T23:56:31-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zmwangx.github.io/blog/2014/11/07/interstellar</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today (I mean November 7, 2014 — it’s technically November 8 at the time of writing) I saw <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Interstellar_%28film%29"><em>Interstellar</em></a> (IMAX digital) at AMC Mercado 20. I rarely go to movie theaters, less on the release day (film formats of <em>Interstellar</em> were released on November 5, and digital formats followed on November 7). However, reviews of it were positive (from the physics community), and I really need a way to release stress these days — I wasn’t in the right condition for months. So I figured I’d just spend an afternoon in front of the big screen.</p>

<p>I’ve heard good things about IMAX 70mm film, like no trailers, among other things. But I didn’t bother the extra seven miles’ drive to Hackworth IMAX Dome, so I landed on IMAX digital. Still a pretty stunning experience, although I ended up watching forty minutes worth of trailers before the real thing (arrived fifteen minutes early). In hindsight maybe I’d be better off spending some extra time on the road.</p>

<p>Speaking of the movie itself, they tried to make it as plausible as possible from a physics viewpoint, by involving <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kip_Thorne">Kip Thorne</a> of Caltech. (There’s even a book out, <em>The Science of Interstellar</em>.) For instance, the wormhole isn’t portrayed as a hole (I mean, imagine a ring in empty space, as you would picture in your mind when you hear the word “hole” out of nothing; that’s not how it looks like here, and there’s a nice explanation). Some of the physics still doesn’t work out quite well, though, like Cooper’s not crushed at the singularity… Also there are communications from within the horizon and breakdown of causality, explained in the movie as happening in four dimension slices of some five dimensional spacetime where time could be a physical dimension. Obviously these are needed to get the sci-fi story going, so no one should be blamed.</p>

<p>I was there for the sci-fi and physics, but a nice surprise was that I was also touched by the humanity elements of story, I mean, family and stuff.</p>

<p>The downside: Cooper’s accent was a bit hard on me ☹</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[2014 Nobel Prize in Physics — LED Lights, Seriously?]]></title>
    <link href="http://zmwangx.github.io/blog/2014/11/06/2014-nobel-prize-in-physics-led-lights-seriously/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-06T11:08:45-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zmwangx.github.io/blog/2014/11/06/2014-nobel-prize-in-physics-led-lights-seriously</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For some reason, I only learned about this year’s laureates today, through <a href="http://motls.blogspot.com/2014/11/ex-employer-wont-meet-blue-led-nobel.html">the reference frame</a>. The prize goes to the inventors of the LED. Not exciting at all, so I don’t care if I’m ever informed. (Lubos has a good point on why applied physics — well, let’s even widen the concept of applied physics a bit — should not surprise anyone when they appear in a Nobel Prize announcement: “After all, Alfred Nobel might have very well considered his dynamite to be a discovery in physics, too.”)</p>

<p>The Nobel Prize Physics Awards has been rather amusing in recent years. Partly due to controversy on the theoretical front and no breakthrough on the experimental front, I guess. (The discovery of Higgs was a breakthrough to some extent, but it was totally expected; little physics beyond SM at LHC before LS1 is sad. Since it was totally expected, the award went to theorists — some experimentalists might not be too thrilled.) Just look at the recent list: 2010, graphene (shouldn’t that be chemistry? if material science can be part of physics, then chemistry must surely encompass it, too); 2009, CCD sensor (whatever that means, maybe that’s important); 2008, fibers (okay, I love fast Internet connections). The list actually goes all the way down to early 20th century, but it’s much denser in recent decades. Now one more: 2014, LED.</p>

<blockquote><p>“for the invention of efficient blue light-emitting diodes which has enabled bright and energy-saving white light sources”</p></blockquote>

<p>Wow, energy-saving. I guess next year’s prize will go to the inventors of high efficiency urinals, for being resource-saving.
<strong>I mean, LEDs are great, but not great as physics, much less a physics breakthrough.</strong></p>

<p>Let’s compare the applied folks to other laureates: Lorentz, J. J. Thomson, Planck, Einstein, Bohr, Heisenberg, Schrödinger, Dirac, Fermi, Pauli, Born, Lee, Yang, Landau, Feynman, Schwinger, Gell-Mann, Weinberg, ’t Hooft, etc. Not on the same level.</p>

<p>It’s good to see that a growing body of physicists are (or at least as it seems to me) increasingly reserved about the Nobel Prize, and prizes in general. Same goes for math, with the Nobel Prize replaced by something else. (Employers still love the big titles, I suppose — good to have some star faculty on board.)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Charles Munger Donated $65M to KITP]]></title>
    <link href="http://zmwangx.github.io/blog/2014/10/24/charles-munger-donated-$65m-to-kitp/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-24T16:41:36-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://zmwangx.github.io/blog/2014/10/24/charles-munger-donated-$65m-to-kitp</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today&rsquo;s news has it that Charles Munger made a $65 million donation to KITP at UCSB. See for instance <a href="http://nyti.ms/1D4zg24">this article</a> on NYT. Of course I didn&rsquo;t learn it from NYT (I&rsquo;m generally sick of any news other than math, physics, or IT-related ones). I learned it from <a href="http://www.math.columbia.edu/~woit/wordpress/?p=7247">Not Even Wrong</a> instead (of course I don&rsquo;t agree with Woit, but some of his links are nice).</p>

<p>I have no interest whatsoever in the business world, so I have no idea about Warren Buffett&rsquo;s business partners (although I&rsquo;m still worldly enough to know Warren Buffett). However, the name Charles Munger sounded surprisingly familiar. After reading the sentence</p>

<blockquote><p>Mr. Munger has frequently donated big sums to schools like Stanford and the Harvard-Westlake School.</p></blockquote>

<p>from the NYT article linked above, it finally hit me that Mr. Munger is the donor of the Munger Graduate Residence here at Stanford. Munger is really nice, much better than our undergrad residences AFAIK (location-wise Roble is still unbeatable for mathematicians and physicists, although Munger still kicks EV&rsquo;s ass).</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m glad to see more and more entrepreneurs funding physics, especially theoretical physics, whether they understand it or not. (<strong>Aside:</strong> Even for laypeople theoretical physics is cool isn&rsquo;t it, like the coolest kid in class. I won&rsquo;t comment on whether math is cooler, but breakthrough mathematical work certainly go largely unnoticed in the public, since theoretical physics is the last thing that laypeople can &ldquo;vaguely understand&rdquo;. Do some name searches on Google to see how math and physics play out in the limelight — hint:</p>

<ul>
<li>Gauss — 4,130,000 results;</li>
<li>Euler — 855,000 results;</li>
<li>Newton — 13,200,000 results;</li>
<li>Einstein — 6,330,000 results.</li>
</ul>


<p>End of aside.) Engaging in physics is plain better than engaging in some questionable philanthropy. (Have you heard that Gates Foundation invested in G4S, the largest private military and security company in the world? I’m not sure about the details — I once read that off a bathroom flyer — but that’s definitely interesting philanthropy.)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
