<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Mathjax | Daily (?) Complaints (?)]]></title>
  <link href="http://zmwangx.github.io/blog/categories/mathjax/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://zmwangx.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-11-25T17:14:10-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://zmwangx.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Zhiming Wang]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why I Abandoned MathJax and Fell Back to PDF]]></title>
    <link href="http://zmwangx.github.io/blog/2014/11/24/why-i-abandoned-mathjax-and-fell-back-to-pdf/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-24T20:54:36-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zmwangx.github.io/blog/2014/11/24/why-i-abandoned-mathjax-and-fell-back-to-pdf</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Recently I wrote an expository article, <a href="/pdf/20141119-convolution-of-irreducible-characters.pdf"><em>Convolution of irreducible characters</em></a>, and posted it <a href="/blog/2014/11/19/convolution-of-irreducible-characters/">here</a>. At first I intended to use MathJax, but in the end I fell back to good ol&#8217; PDF. Here&rsquo;s why.</p>

<p>In short, I&rsquo;m a mathematician. I write math <em>articles</em>, not just standalone expressions or formulas. I use AMSLaTeX to its fullest (not really, but at least I use numbering and the <code>amsthm</code> package to its fullest). HTML simply wasn&rsquo;t designed for this. Here are two influential markup languages designed for totally different use cases, and bridging them is painful. I tried to use <code>pandoc</code>, but it doesn&rsquo;t support <code>\input</code>, doesn&rsquo;t support <code>\def</code>, and swallows <code>\begin{theorem} \end{theorem}</code>, among other things. I tried to use <code>htlatex</code>; even the MathML output is suboptimal, with many math symbols translated to non-math (apart from totally human-unreadable), and it uses its custom CSS files that don&rsquo;t play well with everything else. I tried other things. In the end I gave up. Maybe I don&rsquo;t know enough about MathJax, but I certainly don&rsquo;t want to write a translator myself. Leave LaTeX alone. Distribute as PDF. MathJax may be great for Wikis (like Wikipedia) and for math lite blogs, but it&rsquo;s no replacement for real, beefy LaTeX. It&rsquo;s not for mathematicians who want to distribute real articles.</p>

<p>By the way, Terry Tao and others use <a href="http://lucatrevisan.wordpress.com/latex-to-wordpress/">Luca&rsquo;s LaTeX to WordPress, aka LaTeX2WP</a> for math blogging. From Terry&rsquo;s experience it works fairly well. I don&rsquo;t know if <code>amsthm</code> and <code>\def</code> are in the feature set, though. Anyway, since WordPress handles LaTeX as pre-compiled images (which is also the default on Wikipedia, and which looks poor in general and plays horribly with scaling), LaTeX2WP won&rsquo;t help MathJax users the slightest.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
