<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Storage | Daily (?) Complaints (?)]]></title>
  <link href="http://zmwangx.github.io/blog/categories/storage/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://zmwangx.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-10-28T10:24:20-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://zmwangx.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Zhiming Wang]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[OneDrive Goes Unlimited]]></title>
    <link href="http://zmwangx.github.io/blog/2014/10/27/onedrive-goes-unlimited/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-27T09:44:51-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://zmwangx.github.io/blog/2014/10/27/onedrive-goes-unlimited</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>10/28/2014 Update:</strong></p>

<p>Yesterday Microsoft pushed an update to OneDrive.app to MAS. After uninstalling, reinstalling, and wiping the 10 GB folder I&rsquo;d like to sync (that&rsquo;s for photos; I upload videos via the web interface) on both client and server sides, it actually began to work. The speed was around 1 MB/s during my last sync of 10 GB worth of data. Not fast, but I will be fairly satisfied if it can keep up with that speed. Time will tell.</p>

<hr />

<p>The OneDrive team just <a href="https://blog.onedrive.com/office-365-onedrive-unlimited-storage/">announced on their blog</a> that</p>

<blockquote><p>Today, storage limits just became a thing of the past with Office 365. Moving forward, all Office 365 customers will get unlimited OneDrive storage at no additional cost.</p></blockquote>

<p>Hell, I hate Microsoft, but <strong>I have to say that this is big</strong>. OneDrive might not be the first to offer unlimited cloud storage (not sure), but it is certainly the first one to roll it out on such a grand scale. Remember, Office 365 is just $99.99 a year. OneDrive might not be the best cloud storage service, especially for OS X customers, but unlimited is unlimited — in comparison, I pay Google $9.99 a month for 1 TB.</p>

<p>Microsoft products are indeed pure crap on a Mac. Office for Mac 2011 is horrible (speed and bloat aside, some features are simply not implemented — try to import a UTF-8 CSV into Excel, all non-ASCII characters become underscores; Microsoft’s response was that Unicode import was not implemented yet). OneDrive.app is slow like crawl, and it never finishes syncing — always stuck on the last few megabytes, eating up 100% CPU. Thank god I only use it for backups. The web interface is okay, although Google Drive is faster — blazing fast, I can easily upload with 20+MB/s. But again, <strong>unlimited is unlimited.</strong></p>

<p>Microsoft is opening a new chapter of cloud storage. In today’s world, we have so many huge video files, so storage limit should indeed be something of the past. This is a smart move for Microsoft — when you have, say, 100 TB up there (which seems very far at this moment, but what if all contents go 4K), and if competitors don’t offer comparable plans, then you are stuck with Microsoft. And Office. Oh my god, Microsoft Office must die.</p>

<p>Of course I don’t want to be stuck with Microsoft, so I’m looking at how Google and Apple will handle this. Google ought to offer more affordable plans, preferably also unlimited. (My 1Password still has it that I purchased Office for Mac University 2011 on Nov 12, 2012 for $99.99. That turned into a free 4-year Office 365 subscription, which contains 60 world minutes of Skype per month, 1 TB of OneDrive — oh, now it’s about to go unlimited. All for $99.99. In comparison, Google charges me $119.88 per year.) Apple wants you to save everything to iCloud, and it introduced iCloud Drive and Cloud Kit this year — but plans still start at 5 GB and tops out at 1 TB, seriously? Dude, you sell top notch hardware with huge profits; why don’t you pay your customers back by offering better cloud storage — that’s also better for iCloud.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Disk Visualizer: DaisyDisk]]></title>
    <link href="http://zmwangx.github.io/blog/2014/10/26/disk-visualizer-daisydisk/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-26T00:02:22-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://zmwangx.github.io/blog/2014/10/26/disk-visualizer-daisydisk</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>DaisyDisk is a pretty famous name. I’ve heard a lot that DaisyDisk is beautiful, but as a “power user” I always feel ashamed about using a disk analyzer or visualizer (although no one really cares). I’m pretty comfortable with doing most filesystem operations right in the shell, and for other tasks too tedious for the shell (like renaming a bunch of files with no obvious pattern), Finder (equipped with TotalFinder) works just fine.</p>

<p>Today I was trying clean up my drive a bit, as there were only 22GB left. I knew where the main problem lied: a huge number of highres videos lying in <code>~/vid/staging</code>, awaiting renaming and migration to my external drive. Anyway, it would be nice to have some visualization of a detailed breakdown of my disk usage, preferably on any level I want without multiple passes of <code>du</code>. The name DaisyDisk popped up from the cache in my brain, so I headed over to their website to download it.</p>

<p>The result is not disappointing at all. Look at this:</p>

<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/vyIwSNQ.png" alt="DaisyDisk screen shot" /></p>

<p>Beautiful. Moreover, functional. It indeed gives me a detailed breakdown on any level, within any directory (given enough priviledge). I can also collect items I don’t want and let DaisyDisk clean up for me at once (not surprising for a disk analyzer); this feature isn’t that useful for me since I know exactly where my queues of unorganized items are — <code>~/Downloads</code>, <code>~/aud/staging</code>, <code>~/img/staging</code>, and <code>~/vid/staging</code>.</p>

<p>By the way, DaisyDisk seems to be WinRAR-free. (Rest assured; I’m a good guy and I <em>will</em> purchase a license — these days whether to purchase the website or the MAS version is a headache, though.)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
