<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Disk | Daily (?) Complaints (?)]]></title>
  <link href="http://zmwangx.github.io/blog/categories/disk/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://zmwangx.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-10-27T11:58:35-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://zmwangx.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Zhiming Wang]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Convert Audio CD/DVD to ISO Image on OS X]]></title>
    <link href="http://zmwangx.github.io/blog/2014/10/26/audio-cd-slash-dvd-to-iso-image-on-os-x/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-26T23:29:47-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://zmwangx.github.io/blog/2014/10/26/audio-cd-slash-dvd-to-iso-image-on-os-x</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today it occurred to me that I should make clones of my audio CDs (as stand-alone ISO images, I mean, not just rsyncing the AIFFs to subdirectories in <code>~/aud/lossless</code>). One can never have too many backups.</p>

<p>Of course I could simply pack the aforementioned directories with AIFFs into ISOs — that’s not impressive. The end result might actually be the same, but I want to make the clones directly from the original CDs. It turns out that this is not so simple with the Disk Utility GUI — unlike DVDs, the “New Image” option is grayed out for Audio CDs. I’m not sure why, but maybe they want you to just use iTunes to deal with Audio CDs (which works well for all practical purposes — but theoretical curiosity never ends).</p>

<p>So there comes <code>hdiutil</code>. <code>hdiutil</code> and <code>diskutil</code> are the utilities underlying Disk Utility. Unfortunately, so far I know little about them except for simplest things like <code>diskutil list</code>, <code>diskutil mount</code>, <code>hdiutil attach -stdinpass</code>, etc. (I&rsquo;m so ignorant about anything filesystem related!) The <code>hdiutil</code> verb that makes cross-platform CD or DVD is <code>makehybrid</code>, which supports the following filesystem options: <code>-hfs</code> (holy crap, no HFS+ please! Apple ought to replace this thirty-year-old filesystem — ZFS or something better please!), <code>-iso</code>, <code>-joliet</code>, and <code>-udf</code>. For Audio CDs you use <code>-iso</code> and with <code>-joliet</code> extension:</p>

<pre><code>hdiutil makehybrid -iso -joliet -o AUDIO_CD_NAME.iso SOURCE
</code></pre>

<p>where <code>SOURCE</code> can be the mount point, the disk device file, etc. Similarly, although you can create <code>.cdr</code> images from DVDs via the Disk Utility GUI, you can also do it with <code>hdiutil</code> (which is potentially more portable — I’ve never heard a definitive answer of whether renaming <code>.cdr</code> to <code>.iso</code> really cross-platform):</p>

<pre><code>hdiutil makehybrid -udf -o DVD_NAME.iso SOURCE
</code></pre>

<p>This way CSS keys <em>seem</em> to be cloned as well, since I was able to authenticate such a CSS-protected DVD with <code>libdvdread</code>.</p>

<hr />

<p>P.S. I sincerely hope that one day lossless music tracks are no longer distributed through CD-ROMs. So painful — even my Internet speed is more than ten times faster than the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/CD-ROM#Transfer_rates">highest transfer rate</a> available from any CD-ROM. (I’ve heard about some websites distributing lossless music digitally, but that won’t happen to the music I care about in the near future.) I still like physical albums though — a real sense of possession. Maybe they should contain the physical goodies and some sort of access codes?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Disk Visualizer: DaisyDisk]]></title>
    <link href="http://zmwangx.github.io/blog/2014/10/26/disk-visualizer-daisydisk/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-26T00:02:22-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://zmwangx.github.io/blog/2014/10/26/disk-visualizer-daisydisk</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>DaisyDisk is a pretty famous name. I’ve heard a lot that DaisyDisk is beautiful, but as a “power user” I always feel ashamed about using a disk analyzer or visualizer (although no one really cares). I’m pretty comfortable with doing most filesystem operations right in the shell, and for other tasks too tedious for the shell (like renaming a bunch of files with no obvious pattern), Finder (equipped with TotalFinder) works just fine.</p>

<p>Today I was trying clean up my drive a bit, as there were only 22GB left. I knew where the main problem lied: a huge number of highres videos lying in <code>~/vid/staging</code>, awaiting renaming and migration to my external drive. Anyway, it would be nice to have some visualization of a detailed breakdown of my disk usage, preferably on any level I want without multiple passes of <code>du</code>. The name DaisyDisk popped up from the cache in my brain, so I headed over to their website to download it.</p>

<p>The result is not disappointing at all. Look at this:</p>

<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/vyIwSNQ.png" alt="DaisyDisk screen shot" /></p>

<p>Beautiful. Moreover, functional. It indeed gives me a detailed breakdown on any level, within any directory (given enough priviledge). I can also collect items I don’t want and let DaisyDisk clean up for me at once (not surprising for a disk analyzer); this feature isn’t that useful for me since I know exactly where my queues of unorganized items are — <code>~/Downloads</code>, <code>~/aud/staging</code>, <code>~/img/staging</code>, and <code>~/vid/staging</code>.</p>

<p>By the way, DaisyDisk seems to be WinRAR-free. (Rest assured; I’m a good guy and I <em>will</em> purchase a license — these days whether to purchase the website or the MAS version is a headache, though.)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
