<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Onedrive | Daily (?) Complaints (?)]]></title>
  <link href="http://zmwangx.github.io/blog/categories/onedrive/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://zmwangx.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-11-05T11:42:46-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://zmwangx.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Zhiming Wang]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google Drive — No Selective Subfolder Sync?]]></title>
    <link href="http://zmwangx.github.io/blog/2014/10/28/google-drive-no-selective-subfolder-sync/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-28T20:49:24-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://zmwangx.github.io/blog/2014/10/28/google-drive-no-selective-subfolder-sync</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Up to this point I&rsquo;ve been using Google Drive as an online backup service, and uploads files mostly manually, although I do sync <code>~/img</code> with the client.</p>

<p><strong>Aside.</strong> Google Drive, OneDrive, etc. don&rsquo;t work with symlinks. Wanna keep your stuff free and duplicate-free yet still synced to the servers? Use <code>rsync</code> to automatically reproduce your folder structure with hard links:</p>

<pre><code>rsync -avzP --delete --link-dest=SOURCE/ SOURCE DESTINATION
</code></pre>

<p>e.g.,</p>

<pre><code>rsync -avzP --delete --link-dest=~/img/ ~/img/ ~/sync/GoogleDrive/img/
</code></pre>

<p>automatically reproduces my <code>~/img</code> in the <code>img</code> directory under Google Drive&rsquo;s root, yet every file in the <code>~/img</code> tree is replaced by hard links to the original file, so the new structure within Google Drive takes little additional space — for the directories only.</p>

<p>That doesn&rsquo;t solve every problem though, as you will see shortly. <em>End of aside.</em></p>

<p>So, up to this point I’ve mostly used Google Drive as an online backup service by manually uploading (huge) stuff. But at some point I’m gonna automate parts of the uploading. As it turns out, I can keep some smaller video files on my hard drive; other bigger monsters (like movies, TV shows, etc., especially a lot of 1080i Transport Streams directly from TV broadcasts) are uploaded and then moved to external drives. Some of the smaller files, including things downloaded from YouTube, live in <code>~/vid/etc</code>, and I want to sync this folder to Google Drive. What&rsquo;s shocking is that this is not possible with the Google Drive client — it only allows selective syncing of the top level folders. Let me repeat this:</p>

<p><strong>The Google Drive client only allows selective syncing of the <em>top level folders</em>.</strong></p>

<p>This is <em>insane</em>. It’s almost 2015. Everyone supports this — Dropbox, Microsoft, Box, even Baidu. Google Drive launched on April 24, 2012, that’s 2.5 years ago. <a href="https://productforums.google.com/forum/#!topic/drive/Gs2w1BL-B9U">This thread</a> on Google Drive Forum, “Ability to sync only selected sub folders”, was posted on August 27, 2012, and has garnered 139 replies. They are ignored by the developers, and the accepted “answer” is to utilize Google Drive’s assign-one-file/folder-to-multiple-folders feature to create a special “sync” directory. Okay, that’s a stupid hard link solution on the server side. Okay, if that works… <em>No</em>. “Hard links on the server side” cannot bear different names; so what if I want to sync, say, both <code>vid/etc</code> and <code>aud/etc</code>? Whoops. So I also have to do all sorts of ugly renaming. NO, GOOGLE, NO, I won&rsquo;t accept that much trouble.</p>

<p>This kind of insanity makes me wander:</p>

<p><strong>Do the Google Drive developers use Google Drive themselves?</strong></p>

<p>For now I&rsquo;m moving <code>vid/etc</code> to <code>vid_etc</code>. Sigh.</p>

<hr />

<p>There are other problems that I encountered with Google Drive sync today. For one thing, it rejects what I already have and insists on starting from scratch. I mean, say I have uploaded a folder via the web interface, and later wants to keep it in sync (of course that&rsquo;s only possible if it&rsquo;s top level), so I put what I already have there. Nope, Google Drive reports that as a conflict and insists on downloading all the stuff again. Apart from wasted traffic, that also ruins my hard links, so I have to either wipe everything clean on the server side and reupload, or redownload everything and redo all the hard-linking after the download finishes. Either way, very annoying. I opted for the first one. (I later empirically confirmed that OneDrive could handle this situation.)</p>

<p>There are other problems that don&rsquo;t pop right off my mind. Anyway, the gist is,</p>

<p><strong>Google Drive is not yet sync-ready for power users (maybe even laymen).</strong></p>

<hr />

<p>Then, is OneDrive perfect? No. I know it recently went unlimited, but there’s one major annoyance: the speed. Stanford’s Ethernet speed is almost 1 Gbps UL/DL, but the OneDrive client tops out at about 2 MBps. The web interface isn’t much better. Google Drive is a lot faster than that, which makes it a good backup service for manual uploading. Anyway, maybe OneDrive will improve over time; yesterday they delivered an update to OneDrive.app, and at least it finally works.</p>

<p>OneDrive also boasts no file status indicators on OS X, which everyone else in the industry has. That’s not a show-stopper though, if you just use it as a backup service.</p>

<hr />

<p>What about Dropbox? Dropbox is a truly awesome sync-ready service, but it is at the same time pretty expensive compared to others. Also, since I use Dropbox as a sync service, it must be up at all times and constantly indexing, so I’m really cautious with what I put there to avoid unnecessary cycles and startup time.</p>

<hr />

<p>Everything is broken in one way or another. Sigh. Let&rsquo;s hope that OneDrive improves a lot in the coming months; if it&rsquo;s stable enough and the speed gets some boost, I&rsquo;ll cancel my Google Drive subscription. I am a Google supporter and Microsoft hater, but a service that <em>works</em> is more important than ideology.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[OneDrive Goes Unlimited]]></title>
    <link href="http://zmwangx.github.io/blog/2014/10/27/onedrive-goes-unlimited/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-27T09:44:51-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://zmwangx.github.io/blog/2014/10/27/onedrive-goes-unlimited</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>10/28/2014 Update:</strong></p>

<p>Yesterday Microsoft pushed an update to OneDrive.app to MAS. After uninstalling, reinstalling, and wiping the 10 GB folder I&rsquo;d like to sync (that&rsquo;s for photos; I upload videos via the web interface) on both client and server sides, it actually began to work. The speed was around 1 MB/s during my last sync of 10 GB worth of data. Not fast, but I will be fairly satisfied if it can keep up with that speed. Time will tell.</p>

<hr />

<p>The OneDrive team just <a href="https://blog.onedrive.com/office-365-onedrive-unlimited-storage/">announced on their blog</a> that</p>

<blockquote><p>Today, storage limits just became a thing of the past with Office 365. Moving forward, all Office 365 customers will get unlimited OneDrive storage at no additional cost.</p></blockquote>

<p>Hell, I hate Microsoft, but <strong>I have to say that this is big</strong>. OneDrive might not be the first to offer unlimited cloud storage (not sure), but it is certainly the first one to roll it out on such a grand scale. Remember, Office 365 is just $99.99 a year. OneDrive might not be the best cloud storage service, especially for OS X customers, but unlimited is unlimited — in comparison, I pay Google $9.99 a month for 1 TB.</p>

<p>Microsoft products are indeed pure crap on a Mac. Office for Mac 2011 is horrible (speed and bloat aside, some features are simply not implemented — try to import a UTF-8 CSV into Excel, all non-ASCII characters become underscores; Microsoft’s response was that Unicode import was not implemented yet). OneDrive.app is slow like crawl, and it never finishes syncing — always stuck on the last few megabytes, eating up 100% CPU. Thank god I only use it for backups. The web interface is okay, although Google Drive is faster — blazing fast, I can easily upload with 20+MB/s. But again, <strong>unlimited is unlimited.</strong></p>

<p>Microsoft is opening a new chapter of cloud storage. In today’s world, we have so many huge video files, so storage limit should indeed be something of the past. This is a smart move for Microsoft — when you have, say, 100 TB up there (which seems very far at this moment, but what if all contents go 4K), and if competitors don’t offer comparable plans, then you are stuck with Microsoft. And Office. Oh my god, Microsoft Office must die.</p>

<p>Of course I don’t want to be stuck with Microsoft, so I’m looking at how Google and Apple will handle this. Google ought to offer more affordable plans, preferably also unlimited. (My 1Password still has it that I purchased Office for Mac University 2011 on Nov 12, 2012 for $99.99. That turned into a free 4-year Office 365 subscription, which contains 60 world minutes of Skype per month, 1 TB of OneDrive — oh, now it’s about to go unlimited. All for $99.99. In comparison, Google charges me $119.88 per year.) Apple wants you to save everything to iCloud, and it introduced iCloud Drive and Cloud Kit this year — but plans still start at 5 GB and tops out at 1 TB, seriously? Dude, you sell top notch hardware with huge profits; why don’t you pay your customers back by offering better cloud storage — that’s also better for iCloud.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
