<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Transcoding | Daily (?) Complaints (?)]]></title>
  <link href="http://zmwangx.github.io/blog/categories/transcoding/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://zmwangx.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-10-27T11:58:35-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://zmwangx.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Zhiming Wang]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ripping Copy-protected DVD With Mpv]]></title>
    <link href="http://zmwangx.github.io/blog/2014/10/23/ripping-copy-protected-dvd-with-mpv/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-23T20:03:22-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://zmwangx.github.io/blog/2014/10/23/ripping-copy-protected-dvd-with-mpv</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong><em>10/25/2014 update:</em></strong></p>

<p>I&rsquo;m such an idiot. <code>vobcopy</code> is the real, hassel-free way to go.</p>

<pre><code>brew install vobcopy
</code></pre>

<p>Then, with the DVD mounted,</p>

<blockquote><p><strong>vobcopy</strong> without any options will copy the title with the most chapters into files of 2GB size into the current working directory.</p></blockquote>

<p>Of course there are a ton of options, but I generally hate to browse through options unless I have to, so I&rsquo;m happy with calling without argument.</p>

<hr />

<p>Yesterday I was trying to rip a music video off a newly released DVD from Japan. I knew very little about how DRM (in this case, CSS) actually works and how to break it. I tried to operate directly on the VOB file with <code>ffmpeg</code> or <code>mpv</code> but both failed with a lot of header errors — I suppose more files than the VOB are required for authentication? Whatever, maybe I’ll learn the details in the future, but I don’t see the need since DVD is an outdated technology anyway.</p>

<p>So, can we proceed from here? Most certainly. I noticed that although <code>mpv</code> won’t let me play a single VOB, I can simply hand it the DVD mount point, and it will play the whole DVD seamlessly. <strong>Caution:</strong> <code>mpv</code> needs to be compiled with <code>libdvdnav</code> and <code>libdvdread</code>! With brew you just do</p>

<pre><code>brew install mpv --with-libdvdnav --with-libdvdread
</code></pre>

<p>For better performance and backup, I first cloned the DVD into a <code>.cdr</code> image (DVD/CD-R Master Image) using Disk Utility (I&rsquo;ve never tried creating/cloning image with <code>diskutil</code> CLI, so nothing to report on that). Then I mount the image, say the mount point is <code>/Volumes/UPBX_80165</code>. As said I can hand that mount point to <code>mpv</code> and it simply works, but how about extracting the MPEG-2 video stream? The <code>--stream-capture=&lt;filename&gt;</code> option is there just for you. In principle <code>--stream-dump=&lt;filename&gt;</code> should also work, but without monitoring the output and controlling where to end, I’m not sure if it will ever terminate itself when reading from a DVD (when I stream captured the DVD it just kept repeating itself until I explicitly quit with <code>q</code>). So that&rsquo;s it:</p>

<pre><code>mpv --stream-capture=dump.mpg /Volumes/UPBX_80165
</code></pre>

<p>Then you can torture the <code>dump.mpg</code> with <code>ffmpeg</code> however you want. The most obvious thing is to cut out the music video part, and put into a new container like MPEG-TS. Or transcode it to H.264 for your iPhone. The nice thing about <code>dump.mpg</code> is that, unless I got it wrong, there&rsquo;s no quality loss here — the only thing you got rid of is that goddamn DRM.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
